Okay, there we go. We can now launch the
Hermes desktop. Most AI tools are as
capable at day one as they are at 100.
They don't necessarily learn and evolve
over time. You learn it, but it doesn't
learn you. Hermes is different. The more
you use it, the better it gets at your
specific work, your task, what you want
it to do automatically. Not because you
trained it or told it to do that, but
because it trains itself. It compounds
and learns from its behavior over time.
It's built into the Hermes architecture.
It's by design. It's built by an actual
research company that specializes in
training open models. Hermes by Nous
Research. Nous meaning mind or intellect
in Greek, and Hermes being the messenger
god. So, together we get an agent that
thinks and delivers. Hi, my name is
Callum, also known as Waterloos, and
welcome to today's video on setting up
and running your Hermes agent. AI is
getting better all the time, but it's
still pretty unpredictable. We need ways
to systematize how they operate so that
they do what we want predictably, and
they get better at it over time. Hermes
watches for recurring workflows, writes
reusable skills from them, and then
loads those skills the next time it
recognizes a similar job. In today's
video, I'll show you how to get Hermes
set up in just a few minutes with a
local and a cloud model, how to connect
it to your favorite messaging app so you
can reach your agent from anywhere, how
to run your first automation that
delivers to your phone each day. I'll
also show you why Hermes connects so
naturally to Obsidian and the LLM Wiki
through its existing skills. If you find
this video helpful, please like, hype,
and subscribe as I appreciate your
support a lot. Now, let's set up your
new agent.
There's two major elements that I'm
excited about here. The first is that
it's an agent that grows with you. So,
it gets smarter and better over time. It
learns your preferences. It learns your
workflows. And I'll touch more on that
in a moment. And the other is that it's
open source. It's built by Nous
Research, and their mission statement is
to advance human rights and freedoms by
creating and proliferating open-source
language models, supporting their
unrestricted availability and use, and
furthering their scientific and popular
understanding. So, to me, I think it's
cool that not only do we have an agent
that grows with you and that gets
smarter the more you use it, but it's
built by a company who has open-sourced
it, and their mission statement is to
make AI accessible for everyone. So, I
align very strongly with both of those
for selecting an agent for my personal
and work use. So, it has a persistent
memory, which means it learns your
projects, it automatically generates
skills, and it remembers how it solved
problems over time. You can set up
automation, which we'll get into today.
You can connect to it from anywhere from
all the different messaging agents,
which I'll also talk about today. It can
run parallel agents and sub agents. It
can browse the web, and you can run code
in isolated sandboxes. So, all of these
are pretty cool features that I've been
doing independently across different
tools. So, I'm excited to see them all
bundled together in Hermes. Okay, so
let's get started.
So, I'm going to click download for
macOS. So, I just need to drag this into
my applications folder, and then we can
open it up. Now, one thing I want to
quickly mention is that we can also
install via the terminal if you want to
do this on the command line interface,
but personally, I've really been
enjoying the desktop app. So, I'm going
to show you that today. And it's
installing its own system prerequisites
to make sure it has everything that you
need. Okay, there we go. We can now
launch the Hermes desktop. Okay, so once
the desktop is installed, you can see
that they're suggesting the news portal.
This is their paid service that connects
all the different models together. So,
depending on what you're looking for,
that could be the easiest way to get
going. But before we even connect to
anything like OpenAI or Anthropic, I
want to show you how we can run this
ourselves using a local model. So, I'm
going to click choose provider later,
and then we get brought to the home page
here. So, I just quickly changed my
appearance so you can see a little bit
better. And we can see in the bottom
left here, because I didn't select a
provider, we need to finish setting up
the gateway, which basically just means
we need to connect a model to it.
I'm going to quickly go through setting
up a local model customized for Hermes
today, but if you want a more in-depth
guide, I just put out a video and
accompanying article that walks through
why you should run a local model and how
you can do it step by step with a llama.
A lot of people have been finding that
very helpful, so I recommend watching
that if you're at all confused about
this next section. So, I can press
command or control comma, and that
brings up settings here. And we can see
that we don't have a provider set up
under the model section. So, I'm going
to go here and I'm going to go scroll
down until we get to custom endpoint,
and then I'm going to click set up
custom endpoint, and this pulls up the
option to connect to a locally running
system. So, I'm going to point this to
Ollama. So, Ollama is quite easy to
install. You can just go here and click
download. So, today I'm using the Gemma
4 1, and if you use Gemma 4 latest, that
will give you the E4B, which is good for
running on smaller computers. So, for
example, all I would do is write Ollama
pull Gemma 4 latest, and that would pull
down this Gemma 4 4B version, this one
here. Or, like I've already done is pull
in the 12. So, I'm going to add in the
Ollama endpoint here, which is this one,
and click connect. And now we see that
the gateway is ready. So, basically what
we just did is we connected Hermes to
Ollama. So, now if I click on the model
selector in the bottom here, I can go
down to local and select Gemma 12B. But,
there's one more important piece of
information here. If you want to get a
local model running, I'm going to test
to make sure that we're able to actually
communicate with our local model. So,
I'm going to ask, "What is today's
date?" And the first time you ask a
question, it might take a little while.
But, really what I'm testing here is can
the model run correctly? And we can see,
yes, it got today's date correct. But,
you might end up having it where it pops
up and it says, "I have no idea. I can't
access anything." What that means is
that the model you've selected does not
have sufficient context in order to run
Hermes. So, if I open up my terminal
again, and I type in Ollama ps, we can
see here's Gemma 4 12B, the one that's
currently in use, and its context window
is 32,768.
We can see that a lot of Ollama models
use a 2048 token context limitation, and
Hermes requires 64,000 to give your
agent tools. So, what we can do then is
we can force the context. For example,
here at 32,000, maybe we want to double
that. Maybe we want to up it to 65,000.
So, what we need to do next is we can
create a custom configuration where we
create a separate variant of one of
these models. I'm going to do it for
Gemma 4, and we paste in this prompt
here, where we can see I'm saying create
a file where the context is 65,536,
which is double the current limit, and
then create a variant of that called
Gemma 4 64k. I'm going to click enter.
Now, what we need to do is we need to
change it so that the variant is what is
used here. So, instead of just dealing
with Gemma 4 12B, we want to actually
access that new double context window
that I just created. So, you can ask
Hermes to do this directly if you want,
or you can use this code here, where we
basically are saying Hermes config set
model provider, we want to set it to
this base URL, the one that we've
already done, and we want to set the
default model to Gemma 4 64k. Then,
after quitting and reopening Hermes, if
we go and we click on the model picker
here, we can see now the model has
changed to Gemma 4 64k latest. So, I've
just doubled the working memory of my
local model. So, I'll include all of
those little code snippets that I just
went through there to set it up, but
what you can also do is you can connect
a different model, and you can ask it to
set up these variants and run everything
for you. So, why don't we ask it a
little bit more of a complex question
than just what is today's date?
I'm going to ask what is the latest AI
agent news today. So, you can see that
it's running through its thinking
process to identify which tools it needs
to use, and then it will go through and
run the web search and use the browser
information. So, this might take a
minute or two, and I'll talk a little
bit more about the tools and the skills
in a moment. So, it just went through
some thinking process there, and now
it's opening Google search, and it's
going to go and run this prompt, and
then give me a summary. That took about
2 minutes. What I'm trying to show you
here is all this information, everything
that just happened, is 100% local. This
all is just on my computer. I have
Ollama running, I have Hermes running,
and they're talking to each other, and
Hermes is using Ollama to go run queries
and search the internet. You can
experiment with different local models,
see what works best for you, but if
you're looking for a little bit more
power, or perhaps you're paying for
another service like Codex or Claude
Code, you can connect that model
directly here. So, why don't we do that
now for a minute?
So, what we can do is we can open
settings again. We can go over to
providers, and I'm going to click
OpenAI, and I'm going to sign in to
Codex. And once I get here, then I need
to go back to Hermes for a minute, and I
can copy this code, paste it in, and
this is going to link Codex with Hermes.
There we go. So, now I can select my
default model, or I can click begin. And
now what we can see if I create a new
session is that my default model is
still Gemma 4 12B, but now I have the
option to select from the OpenAI the
Codex models like GPT 5.5. So, what that
means is I now have two different types
of systems I can run here. I can run a
local model if I want to keep everything
private, 100% local, but with less
power, or I can switch to OpenAI or
Anthropic, and I can use a more powerful
model. But what's cool is rather than
just toggling the models between here,
we can actually set up what are called
different profiles down in the bottom
here, where one profile defaults to
using Gemma, the local model, and the
other defaults to using OpenAI.
Each new profile you set up here has a
completely different Hermes environment.
It has a separate configuration, skills,
and soul.md. But rather than have me set
this all up, what I can do is I can
switch over to Codex, for example, and I
can just ask it to set up its own
profile system. So, just as a pro tip,
if you're ever getting stuck on
something, or really you want to do
anything, you might as well ask Hermes
to do it for you and see if it can
handle it. If it can't do it off the
bat, you can give it a little bit more
information or manually set it up, but
over time it will learn what you're
trying to do here. And it might be able
to just do it on its own. So, we'll see
that in a moment. So, we can see here
it's actually running code. It's running
create profile, create config path. So,
it's building separate profiles, one for
local and one for cloud. That makes it
really easy for me to just click between
the different profiles once they appear
down here. So, we can see now it says it
created and verified both profiles. It
gave it one called Gemma 4, the other
called Codex, and they were cloned from
the default. Now, if I close Hermes, and
I reopen it, we can see that we now have
Codex, and we have Gemma 4. So, now we
can see if I click on home, it defaults
to Gemini 4 64K. If I click on Codex, it
switches over to GPT 5.5, and if I click
over to Gemini 4 specifically, it
defaults to Gemini 4. So, I now have two
different profiles that have completely
different configurations, and each use
different models depending on the task.
By clicking on the profile, you get a
separate list of sessions, you get
different skills. Everything is isolated
between these two. So, now we have the
whole chat system set up. We have our
local model, and we have our cloud
model. So, we've got power, and we have
privacy. Now, I want to quickly show you
some of the more interesting features of
Hermes in the settings before we get
into a practical example.
So, the first one is if we click on
skills and tools across the top, we can
see that there are 71 skills built into
this. Basically, a skill is a reusable
workflow that the agent can use, so that
if you ask it to do something, rather
than the agent trying to reason through
what you mean and how you mean it, it
can go pull one of these skills, so it
does it repeatedly. It significantly
increases the quality and consistency
and repeatability of how you use your
agent. So, I recommend going through and
just exploring and taking a look at what
the different skills are, because the
more you can piece these skills
together, the more you're going to get a
workflow that works best for you. For
example, I use Obsidian a lot, and I'll
talk about this more later, and there's
specifically a skill on how to use
Obsidian. So, that means that we can use
Hermes to connect to Obsidian and write
notes for us, or perhaps build itself an
LLM wiki, which I talk more about in my
video on why and how to build an LLM
wiki. So, I recommend checking that out
if you want to go deeper into it. There
is actually an LLM wiki here, and if
you're interested in seeing how we can
connect Hermes to the LLM wiki, let me
know in the comments. I'm happy to make
a dedicated video that works through how
to connect Hermes to Obsidian, and
specifically how to work through
building the LLM wiki. So, I just think
it's really cool that we can use
Obsidian as a memory layer for AI. We
also have tool sets, and this is where
you can enable different functions. For
example, maybe you don't want your agent
to be able to run code, you you turn it
off. Maybe you don't want it to be able
to use your computer, you can turn that
off. The goal here and why a lot of
people are enjoying Hermes over Open
Claw is that you have a little bit more
transparency and control as a less
technical user on how your agent's
operating. One thing I recommend keeping
on is memory because this will build
persistent memory across sessions. So,
for example, if we go over to the Hermes
folder, which is a hidden folder on Mac,
and we go over to memories here, this is
where the agent's going to create a
user.md file and a memory.md file. And
these are files that it will update on
its own outside of the session context.
So, for example, I just told the agent,
just so that it understands me better,
I'm a technical person who prefers
straight to the point information,
fairly sophisticated with my knowledge,
but I also prefer seeing how the pieces
fit together so that I learn along the
way. So, we can see here that this
triggered a memory. So, it added a line
to the user file. So, if we go back to
our folder here and go to memories, we
can now see that there's a user.md file
where I told Hermes what it is that I
like, and it created a little summary
here saying user's technical and prefers
straight to the point sophisticated
information that explains how pieces fit
together so they can learn along the
way. So, this is where we really get
into the self-evolving nature of Hermes
where as I discuss and as I talk about
different things, whether it's projects
or me or just things I'm interested in,
the agent will continuously build out
its persistent memory so it gets better
over time and it can even build its own
skills based on what it's learning from
me so that it creates a workflow that
gets smarter and more efficient for me
specifically over time.
If you ever have any questions about any
of this or you want to figure out how to
set up anything in particular, I
recommend checking out the docs because
there's a lot of information to get you
going and you can always point your
agent at these docs and it will be able
to read it and then do a better job
answering your question and helping you
get things set up. Now, before I get
into messaging, let's take a look at
some of the other settings for a second.
One thing that I really want to
emphasize here before I get into all the
rest of the the is if we go to advance,
we can see that we have execution back
end. We can control how code is
executed, how the terminal is executed,
whether you want this running locally on
your main system, running in a Docker
container, running through a VPS, or
SSH, which is where you can connect
different computers together. Rather
than having it just run in whatever the
root folder is on your computer, giving
it access to everything on your
computer, you can put it in a sandbox
inside of a Docker container. You're
able to protect the rest of your
computer from any code or operations
that Hermes might be doing an error or
just getting wrong. That is something I
just really wanted to point it out at
the beginning because it's exceptionally
important. I've already shown you the
model where we get everything set up
here. We can add different personalities
for the chat. There's a lot of different
options here, so you can pick what works
best for you. You can change the
appearance here. You can control the
working directory. So right now, for
example, I'm having everything operate
in just the root folder, but I could
have this go elsewhere. And what's nice
is you can configure this on a per
profile basis, too. So maybe ChatGPT
operates out of one folder and Gemma
operates out of another. That way we can
keep the separation of information
between our private and our cloud
providers. We also have controls over
the memory and context, like I
mentioned. So this is where it's
creating that memory.md file and a
user.md file. And we can also control
what we want for the budget on how much
information is stored. So basically what
that means is Hermes will prune out of
date information over time to keep the
memory file small so that when it gets
injected into new chats, it doesn't take
up too much space. So we can also get
into building a separate memory layer.
I'm using something like Hindsight or
Honcho or Nemesis, which is one that I'm
exploring. So if you're interested in
seeing how to build a memory stack for
Hermes, let me know in the comments and
I'm happy to make a dedicated video on
that. And that's where we would get
into, for example, the memory provider
here. We can also get into voice, which
all happens 100% locally, depending on
the settings that you're using here. One
final thing before we get into our
practical example is that I want to
mention you can also set up different
gateway connections. So right now I have
this set as a local gateway, which means
that this computer I'm on right now is
what is running Hermes, and this is
where the back end is created. If I want
to keep this running on my desktop, but
connect to it through my laptop, I can
run my laptop as a remote gateway that
then connects to this back end. So, I
don't want to get too much into that
right now, but what's nice about that is
especially if you have a memory system
that you've built, you can keep all of
your memories on one computer, but still
write to it from another computer, so
that you're building one agent that
continues to mature across multiple
devices with a single memory bank.
There's one shared brain for different
devices. Let me know if you want me to
make a video on that, I'm happy to. It's
something that I'm personally very
interested in. We can also add API keys,
so we can get more control over the
different systems that we're using,
whether it's for memory, for tool
calling, for coding, for browsing.
There's a lot we can do here. And of
course, we can connect to model context
protocol. So, I know that was a lot of
information. Please let me know if you
have any questions, I'm happy to go into
it more.
If you're finding this video helpful,
just a reminder to please like and
subscribe, as I appreciate your support
a lot. If you're looking for more ways
to support me, please also consider
joining my membership on YouTube or
Patreon. I give my members access to
skills, tools, tips, and insights on how
we can use these tools more effectively
to make our lives easier. I'll also be
getting some of the skills and the
workflows that I'm building in today's
video to my members. Now, let's keep
building. For me, I think the best way
to get started is to consider what is it
that I do every day or once a week that
I wish could be made easier or obsolete.
There's probably some way to automate or
significantly improve your productivity
by having an agent that understands you
the more you do that thing. So, take a
look through the skills, take a look
through the tools, have a chat with
Hermes about how Hermes can help you,
and it will learn and write skills and
get better over time. So, I thought that
a good example and one that will show
how we can actually connect messaging,
which means that we can bring in
chatting over Telegram or Signal or
email or text. What I was thinking is
what if I had a daily briefing bot that
messaged me updates on AI each day. That
way I can do deep dives into what I care
about instead of just initially scanning
the news to get surface level
information. And then over time, I can
give more feedback to Hermes based on
that daily briefing. So, the briefing
gets more and more customized based on
what I'm specifically interested in. And
the best part is that rather than just
having to open my computer to do this, I
could access it from my phone or from my
Discord or from anywhere else. And this
is what's called a messaging gateway.
We're able to message from something
like WhatsApp or Slack or Google Chat or
Discord or Telegram or text or email.
There's a whole list here, and it all
has a conversation that gets stored in
your back end. So, what we're doing is
we're creating a messaging gateway. So,
the easiest one to get going is often
Telegram. So, why don't we do that
today? We'll get the Telegram messaging
gateway set up, and then we will
schedule an automation that will run
that daily briefing. So, for all of
these different tools here, there is a
dedicated setup guide on Hermes. So, I
recommend taking a look if you need to.
But for Telegram, we just need two
things. We need to create a bot with the
BotFather, which is just you can just
search BotFather on Telegram, and then
paste the token it gives me. And then we
need to allow a certain Telegram user ID
to communicate with our Hermes back end.
So, this is my phone right here where I
have Telegram set up. So, I just clicked
on BotFather, and I can click create new
bot here. So, I'm going to call this
wanderloots_hermesbot.
Click create bot. Now, I need to get an
API key here. So, I'm going to copy
this. And then now what I need to do,
since I have this API key, is I need to
go and get my Telegram user ID. So, now
the one I just went to was called the
raw data bot, and this is what's going
to get me my ID. There we go. So, I just
put in my ID, click save changes. Okay,
so once we have the bot token in there
and we have our Telegram user ID in
there, this allows us to connect
directly to the bot, and this allows me
to be the only one to connect to the
bot. So, you can see it says messaging
gateway stopped, disconnected. What we
can do is we can go down to the bottom
here, click gateway ready, click on the
open systems panel, and then click
restart messaging. And now we see
gateway restart is running. And we go
over to Telegram, and we see that we are
connected. All right, so now that I have
that Hermes bot, I can click on it here,
and I I click start. We can see there's
now one agent running. Now, if I just
type in hi, we can see my bot is
responding to me. So, this is me having
a conversation with the default model
running on my system here. And we can
configure which model we want to use. I
was trying to use it with Gemma and it
was struggling a little bit. There's
probably some time out duration that I
would need to fix here. But, when I
switched it to ChatGPT, it works
completely fine. So, for example, I say,
"Who are you?" And it says, "I'm Hermes
agent, an AI assistant running via your
Hermes desktop set up by News Research."
And it's able to identify
We now have a direct messaging system
for my phone to this agent running on my
computer. So, that's pretty cool. I can
see I have the actual conversation right
here inside of my system. So, this is
being saved to my computer. So, now what
I'm going to do is I'm going to actually
run my session here. So, I'm going to
say, "What's the goal?"
I'm actually planning out what I want my
daily briefing bot to be. So, I told
GPT-5 here just to get everything set up
correctly. I want to get the most
updated relevant information on AI each
day. Message me once on Telegram with
the key information, and then to learn
from the feedback I give you. Then I
told it, "Please don't start yet. Just
make a plan here." Because the goal for
me is not just to get whatever the
high-level news is. I want to get a very
curated information stream for myself.
One that as I give feedback to my agent
gets better over time. So, based on my
prompt, here's the implementation plan.
It's going to create a new skill called
AI Daily Intel, which will become the
brain of the daily report that gets
better over time based on a whole bunch
of information. Then it'll create a
daily cron job, which we'll talk about
more in a moment, that will be able to
run autonomously to deliver it to my
Telegram chat. Again, I might also have
it emailed it to me. It's completely up
to you how you want this to happen. So,
just before it begins, I like to always
give feedback to please ground its plan
in the actual Hermes docs so that it can
better understand its limitations versus
what it may or may not be hallucinating.
For example, cron jobs don't have
messaging history to them. Everyone
starts as a fresh session. So, I want to
make sure that if it is pulling
information, it's pulling it not from
its messaging history from Telegram, but
from its memories that could be in
Obsidian or just generally in the
session data. And you can see here that
it has gone through and said this is the
order of implementation. It's going to
confirm when, confirm what, create the
skill, and then run a dry run to make
sure it all works, and then adjust the
skill based on the feedback. So, this is
where we truly get into this
self-evolving system because every day
it messages me, I can give it some
feedback, it will write the feedback
into the skill, and then tomorrow's
version works even a little bit better.
So, it's going to create one skill, the
daily intel. It's going to run once per
day, and when the cron job, which is an
automation, we see cron down here
scheduling. If we click new cron, we can
choose what we want it to be called, how
often it runs, where it delivers to, and
what the prompt is. So, within this
prompt, you can also reference a
specific skill, so that as the agent
runs, when I read a report in Telegram,
I can give feedback, for example, more
like number two, less on funding, deeper
into agent workflows, and then the
normal Hermes Telegram chat replies to
it, interprets the feedback, and then
updates the skill that then gets loaded
tomorrow. So, after even just a few
days, it should improve itself over
time. So, one piece of advice is that
before you try running an automation as
a cron job, it's better first to have it
run in the chat, so you can see what
it'll look like before you try and
automate it. That way you can tweak it
up front instead of being disappointed
when it runs poorly tomorrow. We can
always click in and see the skills. For
example, here is one skill it has on
skill authoring, so I'm building its own
skills, and now it's going to go and
manage the skill itself. So, it just
created that new skill here, the daily
intel, and this is just a markdown file,
and we can just open that file if we
want. And this is where Obsidian comes
in because Obsidian would be able to
read this, I'd be able to open this in
Obsidian and modify it myself each day,
and then the next time the automation
runs, it would be updated. Okay, there,
so it just ran for a couple minutes, and
this is what the dry run report would
be. Seems like a good summary so far,
and it looks like it gave me the top
seven pieces of news. And I can just
give a little bit of feedback here and
tell it, "Hey, you know what? I want to
understand not just about the technical
information, but also why it matters for
the average person." So, now we can see
that the agent is going through, it's
viewing the skill, and then it's
managing it to update it to include
another lens for this type of
information. So, that's where we get
into this self-evolving nature where
each report I get, I can give feedback
on what I like and what I don't like.
And maybe after a couple weeks of doing
this, I get a really curated piece of
information every day. So, like I
mentioned before, we now need to
schedule the cron job, which is
scheduling the automation, and then we
want it to be delivered to Telegram. So,
we can see here the agent just went and
it updated the cron job, and now we have
this cron job that just appeared on the
side. So, you can manually do that by
setting it yourself, but what I'm trying
to hammer home here is that everything
you want to do in this system shouldn't
be done manually. Once you get it set
up, you should just be asking your agent
to do it, and if it doesn't do it right,
give it feedback and it will learn over
time. So, now we can click on this cron
job, and we can take a look at it, and
we have it set to run in 1 minute. So,
we'll see how it goes. Also, there is an
option to just trigger now, but I wanted
to see how the automation worked. And
one thing that's worth noting is that
you're able to actually attach skills to
a particular cron job. So, if we go and
we open the file here, we can see that
here is the prompt that we gave it, and
here is the skill that's attached to it.
This is where you're able to add as many
skills as you want and have those run
automatically, and all you need to do is
now tweak the skill and tweak the prompt
until it gets better over time. Or, like
I mentioned, even better, have the agent
do it itself for you. We can see we've
got this countdown on the side here, so
let's see what happens with our
Telegram.
All right, so I just had to go through
and make a few tweaks. Took me probably
three or four tries to get it working
like I wanted. This is where it's all
about recalibrating, about iterating
until you get it right. I now have my
cron job, which is going to run every
day at 8:00 a.m. We can see the full
prompt inside of here, and it's pulling
in the skill that I had chat GPT build
out for me. If I pull up Telegram again,
we can see that I had a reply from the
Hermes bot and it gave me a briefing
where it pulled in the three most
important bigger picture perspectives on
AI news. For example, that research
agents can leak secrets through their
search queries. That's pretty important.
This is actually something I had to deal
with as a patent agent and intellectual
property lawyer where if you're doing
Google searches, it's actually possible
that you could be disclosing inventions.
So, that's something interesting that
agents could have that. And then there's
a few more pieces of news here, the top
rated ones. And what's cool is I gave it
some feedback just saying that's much
better. I like all three of these
stories. And the agent replied, "Okay,
cool. I saved this preference." If I go
back to the Telegram chat here, we can
see that I actually had the reply here
and the agent updated its memories based
on my feedback. So, that's all working
perfectly now. I have every day the
agent is going to run a search on the
web, pull information based on my
particular query, and then message me on
Telegram with the report where I can
then give it feedback and it will learn.
So, a few things I learned here,
we had to make it clear that we wanted
it to use the browser, not web, because
web requires external API keys. If
there's browsers that block particular
automation, then you might want to
either use a different browser or
suggest a different search. So, this is
something that we want to continue
updating over time. And as another
thought, if I go over to my Telegram, we
can see that it only updated the memory,
which means that inside of our file
here, inside of memory and user, it
updated itself, but it didn't update the
skill itself. So, what I'm doing right
now is I have the agent going and it's
running a separate automation that every
day before the next one runs, it's going
to schedule a second cron job and that
cron job is going to go in and read my
feedback here and then update the skill.
So, I have the skill updater cron job
that runs before the next daily report
and then the daily report that will use
the updated skill to give me a better,
more personalized daily report. So, I
hope you can see how this is starting to
get into that self-learning system, the
self-evolving system where we can have
an agent that runs on its own, that
pulls in information, messages it to me,
I give it feedback, and then that
updates the system so that tomorrow is
even better. So, there's a lot more that
we could do here. A next step would be
that we could bring in the daily
reports. I could flag the ones that I
like the most, and we could use the LLM
Wiki skill that I was talking about to
ingest this into our LLM Wiki, but I'm
not going to touch too much on that
right now because I have a dedicated
video that goes deeper into why you
might want to have an LLM Wiki, and then
how we can set it up as well. So, if
you're interested, I'm also happy to
show you how I would connect Hermes to
my LLM Wiki, so I can make that into
another video. Some other things that
I'm interested in exploring further is
building a memory stack using memory
providers, and then also linking my
laptop to my desktop so that we can have
this single memory system working across
multiple devices. We can also get into
running the execution in a Docker or
somewhere remotely. And there's also a
web UI and dashboard that shows you
different statistics and telemetry on
what you're building here, so that's
something that you can explore if you
want to operate more efficiently. But
for now, I'm going to continue exploring
Hermes. I'm going to keep having
conversations, building out this memory
system for myself, building out this
customization so that in the future
everything should be running
automatically, and the agent learns with
every piece of feedback I give it.
You now got a local agent running
connected to a local model that sends
you a daily briefing each day, and a
system that's already better than it was
an hour ago. Without you having to do
anything extra, just by having a chat
and asking Hermes to work with you. And
we've barely scratched the surface of
what Hermes can do, and why I'm so
excited to use it. I'm working on more
videos on how to connect to Hermes from
multiple systems, how to connect to
Obsidian and the LLM Wiki. Let me know
in the comments if you have any
questions about what I talked about
today, or if there's any workflows that
you would like to see me build, as I'm
happy to help you out and make more
videos. If you found this video helpful,
just a reminder to please like and
subscribe, as I really appreciate it.
Thanks again for watching, and I will
see you in the next video.